<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.4.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-03-07T12:58:52+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Asia Much?!</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Aboard the train from Manzhouli to Beijing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/china/2017/02/11/Man_Bei.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Aboard the train from Manzhouli to Beijing" /><published>2017-02-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-02-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/china/2017/02/11/Man_Bei</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/china/2017/02/11/Man_Bei.html">&lt;p&gt;*Booking: Can be done on the official China Rail website but apparently need a Chinese mobile number and ID to do it, on ctrip website but it is delivered to only major cities as of Feb2017, there are many agents who book the train tickets for a charge of about 6USD per ticket (change of train is considered a new ticket)+delivery charge+payment surcharge if using PayPal or credit card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*WiFi: available but only for Chinese mobiles and in any case the landing page is almost always in Chinese&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Money: No card payment possible on train&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Language: English not widely spoken, so be prepared with some standard Chinese phrases. Even better write it down and point-shouldn’t be so hard with all the translation apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Tips: Smoking is permitted on trains in designated areas. Food can be bought on the train either in the canteen or the pushcarts. 220V charging points in every compartment of the soft sleeper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We head down to the train station to board our train to Beijing. Train station security checks are straight forward. id check, ticket check followed by xray of baggage and body scan. people are not allowed on the platform until the train arrives. everyone has to wait in waiting rooms and they are opened once the trains are ready to board. tickets are checked before boarding. we had booked soft sleeper which is a 4 person compartment with baggage place under seats and also some “attic” space. Hot water is available, food and drink carts pass by often. 220V charging points are available so is WiFi, access with some China specific apps. The facilities in general are OK. However the toilets are not that clean and sometimes the water in the wash area or sink can run out (as it happened).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0630.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t plan your trip in the high season or around it and try to avoid peripheral stations like changping bei (bei is north in Chinese. Beijing was the capital of the north in old China) since getting to Beijing Nan(Nan being south in Chinese) (for the high speed train) would be a hassle (2 hour metro ride, or about for a dist of about 112 km)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have the company of a very friendly family with roots in Mongolia. we hear stories of traditional celebrations with family accompanied with food, drink, music (impromptu singing). Roasted nuts are a staple snack to chat over. We are told stories of favorite past times in  their culture, punctuated in between by a very spunky 3 year old kids talk. we are also offered tips of navigating Beijing and offered some desert oranges&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scenery passing us by is very varied. From the grasslands of inner Mongolia to hilly regions proceeding down south. Vast farmlands to crowded cities. All the variety of scenery and people breaks up the monotony of the train travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0642.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0644.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0654.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0666.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0696.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0700.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0707.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0748.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0760.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0765.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG2256.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG2274.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG2275.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traveling is always fun hearing some stories from the local part of the world&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently foreigners or foreign looking persons are not very common on these trains. Result, i get one more celebrity or peculiar zoo animal experience (just kidding!). When we walk into the pantry, the chef welcomes us like we are the captain of the train and especially puts on the apron and makes it a point to personally come collect our order. He does not speak much English but is generally very interested to talk to us and wants to take the best possible care of us guests. For lunch we have some chopped potatoes with vegetables and rice, at the end of the meal he comes by again and offers to pour some hot water into our rice bowl, apparently a way of finishing the meal. The celebrations of the Chinese new year still seemed to be going on even though the date was Feb10. He also offers to make sticky rice sweets just for us. Very friendly! The captain of the train and some train staff are also in the pantry and crew in general are very jovial and joke around (like commenting that a comb will be gifted to a bald crew member present in the group for the spring festival). A meal costs an average of 40Yuan. There are also push carts that pass by in the compartments selling Chinese version of porridge, sweets, chips, soft drinks, steamed corn and lunch set meals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smoking is allowed on Chinese trains between compartments and if the doors don’t/wont be shut the smoke enters the cabins and stays there. So be prepared for that, we had a hellish ride in the second half of the train ride because of that. Cigarettes are even sold on the push carts!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the time around the Chinese new year and was such a joy to look at the houses irrespective of how rich or poor it looked, to be decorated with red lanterns and Chinese writing of prosperity and good wishes. this was a constant theme in all the villages and city we passed through on the way to Beijing. Even the life-stock (cows, donkeys, sheep) were sometimes marked with red. We even caught glimpses of a dragon dance very briefly. Later as the sunset and we were passing through various villages and cities there was this non stop fireworks lighting up the night in some spectacular show. A very interesting and unexpected experience!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0724.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0743.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0768.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0800.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been a  pleasant journey with friendly co passengers, a very warm train crew, stunning landscape from Inner Mongolia to Beijing, watching the festivities of spring season in the villages we rush by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up .. Nightmare in Beijing??&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">*Booking: Can be done on the official China Rail website but apparently need a Chinese mobile number and ID to do it, on ctrip website but it is delivered to only major cities as of Feb2017, there are many agents who book the train tickets for a charge of about 6USD per ticket (change of train is considered a new ticket)+delivery charge+payment surcharge if using PayPal or credit card.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">In inner Mongolia,Manzhouli</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Manzhouli" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="In inner Mongolia,Manzhouli" /><published>2017-02-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-02-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Manzhouli</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Manzhouli">&lt;p&gt;*Getting there: Manzhouli has its own airport. But train is cheaper, direct trains from Beijing are available. Speed trains do not serve Manzhouli as a destination as of 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*WiFi: Poor. Public wifi hot-spots cant be connected to without a Chinese mobile number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Money: Visa/MasterCard accepted in very few establishments. Mobile payment is the preferred mode of payment. Cash otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Language: English not widely spoken, so be prepared with some standard Chinese phrases. Even better write it down and point-shouldn’t be so hard with all the translation apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Tips: Dress warm in Winter!!!! Explore the local food culture and maybe go shopping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Manzhouli is a very peculiar city, brightly lit, big buildings and shopping malls. This is in sharp contrast to the border town in Russia. Approaching Manzhouli already felt like Vegas, a sparkling city blanketed otherwise by nothingness and shadows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0585.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Manzhouli is really cold in winter, but apparently still warmer and expecting upto -40C normally.We check into a hostel with attached bathroom for 10Eur a night. The hostel has a very distinct Mongolian feel along with idols in Genghis khan, Mao, Stalin and Lenin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0606.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0607.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0608.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We meet a very skilled player of a type of Chinese stringed instrument called Guzheng and he courteously plays for us a piece epitomizing the mountains and rivers. Such a beautiful piece it was, it was so easy to envision along with him the sound of water in the music itself. he has been playing the instrument for 13 years and on a work-away vacation and plans to become a professional musician later. This is a description of the instrument from chinawhisper.com website “The Guzheng is a Chinese plucked zither. It is made of 18-23 or more strings and movable bridges. People believe that it has been invented during the Warring States Period (475-221 BC).  The performer pluck the strings at the right portion with right hand, and left hand presses the string on the left side of the bridge to produce pitch ornamentation and vibrato. The skilled player can create sounds that can evoke the sense of waterfall, thunder, and even the scenic countryside.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;object&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;autostart&quot; value=&quot;false&quot; /&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;src&quot; value=&quot;/assets/china/music.mp3&quot; /&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;autoplay&quot; value=&quot;false&quot; /&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;controller&quot; value=&quot;True&quot; /&gt;
&lt;embed src=&quot;/assets/china/music.mp3&quot; controller=&quot;true&quot; autoplay=&quot;false&quot; autostart=&quot;false&quot; type=&quot;audio/mp3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/object&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Loved the Manzhouli food culture. The biggest shopping mall in town has a full floor dedicated to a eatery with a wide variety of cuisine in different stalls on offer. I choose a kind of Korean dish with rice and cooked vegetables in a hot stone bowl. The idea is that the ingredients get slightly scalded by coming in contact to the hot stone bowl. The ingredients have to mixed together and must be stirred continuously. Sea weed soup to go along with it. The portions are really generous. There are other options as well like vegetables deep fried in oil and topped with seasonings, hotpot on a conveyor belt, steamed buns. The fate of the vegetarians are looking up! Average meal costs about 10-18Yuan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0593.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0597.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0598.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0610.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0612.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;China has their own network of credit card providers, so visa is not entirely accepted at all merchants. but finding a bank with ATM is not very hard. What is also very common is mobile payment. We would also see it elsewhere in China, they are used by all service providers from street food vendors to shopping malls and beyond. It seems to be a social media network, chat platform and payment platform rolled into one. Extremely convenient, maybe not very privacy friendly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Manzhouli seems to offer much more in the Summer and is also the peak season. We leave for Beijing after an overnight stop.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">*Getting there: Manzhouli has its own airport. But train is cheaper, direct trains from Beijing are available. Speed trains do not serve Manzhouli as a destination as of 2017.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Transmanchurian-the train journey through the snow globe and beyond</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Transmanchurian" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Transmanchurian-the train journey through the snow globe and beyond" /><published>2017-02-04T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-02-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/transsib</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Transmanchurian">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0145.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Booking the ticket: rzd.ru can be used to book national routes online on an English page. International routes have to bought through an agent or in person at the train station. So get creative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Amenities on the train: Hot water for drinking. Can also be used to prepare ready made meals. Canteen is available on train but with very limited vegetarian options (Cup noodles can also be bought). Drinks can also be bought. Food can also be bought at the platform where the train stops (Stop time range from a couple of mins to an hour or more). Shower has been apparently discontinued. Toilets are kept very clean. Ample storage space for luggage (we had two 90L backpack which could easily fit in the space above our compartment). Doors in the first class compartment can be locked from the inside. Blankets and pillows and towels are provided. Compartments are vacuumed once a day. Charging points (220V AC) are available (4 points for every compartment).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*WiFi: No Wifi is available on the train&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Money: We paid with cash. But the canteen seemed to have a card reader (maybe only works if the station halts at a major station)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Language: English not widely spoken, so be prepared with some standard Russian phrases. Even better write it down and point-shouldn’t be so hard with all the translation apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Tips:Temperatures in the cabins are maintained at a comfortable 22-24C. Warm clothes needed only for the outside. Toilets are locked for 15 mins before arriving and after departing from every station. Most of the shopping for groceries and food can be done beforehand at the many convenience stores in and around the train station. ATM machines available at the Yaraslavsky train station. At Zabaikalsk (Russian border town to China) the wheels of the compartments are changed and passport checks are done in the train (depending on number of passengers), the toilets are closed during this time so make sure to listen to natures calls and use the toilet at Zabaikalsk station before boarding the train again. Available options to book first class compartment(SV) - 2 berth compartments, second class(Kupe) - 4 berth compartments, third class (platskart). Options seems to be available for gender specific compartments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Trans-Siberian rail has three main rail routes (journey can also compose of shorter legs) Trans-Siberian which runs from Moscow to Vladivostok (9298km over 6days); Trans-Mongolian goes through Russia,Mongolia and China, starting at Moscow-Ulaanbaatar-Beijing (7826km about 6days); Trans-Manchurian which goes through Russia and China, Moscow-Beijing(8988km over 6days). We booked our ticket online at rzd.ru. Online ticket is provided which must be exchanged for tickets at the train station (counter or automated machines).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG2221.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Historically, the Trans-Siberian rail was envisioned by the Tsars to transform Russia in the industrial age  in the 19th century among other goals. The construction of the epic rail-route of the 19th century was shadowed by financial issues, geographical and meteorological challenges and  human resource problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We take train 20 on the trans-Manchurian rail between Moscow and Beijing and plan to get off at the Chinese border town of Manzhouli. Yaraslavsky station is the departing station. After passing through the security check we end up in the waiting room for the train to arrive. The station is surprisingly empty of crowd for a major station in the capital of the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our train arrives 30 minutes before departure and we make our way to board the train. Looking forward to getting comfortable in our first class cabin. Our passports get checked and the obligatory attempt by the train attendant to pronounce my last name, don’t know how many different variations I have heard of it, but will add Russian to it now. At the end of succeeding to say my name, the Provodnitsa purses her lips gives a thumbs as if to congratulate herself on managing such a superhuman feat of pronunciation. The cabins are really very comfortable (first class eh, not often you can afford that!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Provodnitsa who are in charge of keeping the compartment in order have a very interesting personality. They are generally women and always keep an eye out what people are doing in the corridors of the compartment and outside the train usually with a frowning look. No need to reach for your armour yet, they are generally friendly and very competent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0564.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two person cabins in the first class, with a water heater at the end of each compartment, dispensing boiling water all the time. toilets are very clean and there are just 3 cabins occupied out of 10 cabins, so very sparse.Which is quite natural since we are traveling in the low season. We are given blankets and bed spreads. The canteen is also well equipped basically you can buy everything on board or at the station stops provided one is willing to pay a little bit more. There is enough storage space to store at least two 70l backpacks at the top and about two 50l backpacks under the seat. Inside temperature are a comfortable 20-24C, main cabins are isolated through two doorways. Yes, the outside is very cold.The outermost doorways already had ice creeping up on the frames and handles, so don’t lick the door handle!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0226.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did i already say it is really comfortable in first class? just sit back, read a book, play some games, snack or drink and watch the country pass by and comment on the peculiarities of a country running past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0217.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0219.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0249.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0250.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0272.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0304.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0311.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0316.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0317.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0319.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0488.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0510.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0557.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0560.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The train stops along the way and there are opportunities to get off and walk about and buy some things, the time in all train stations are in Moscow time but there are about 11 time zones in Russia which lead to some very peculiarities. One of the shortest days we encountered was on the third day. getting up at around 8 am and getting into darkness already at 2pm (Moscow time). The worst is at Zabaikalsk which is a full 6 hours ahead of Moscow but the trains still follow Moscow time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The approximate average speed is 60kmph and this lets you watch the towns big and small pass you by, sunrise and sunsets many. From the populated regions European Russia with  Yekaterinburg and passing through Vladimir which has amongst the oldest churches in Russia. Leading onto Taiga and Siberia with steady landscapes that can be subtitled ‘winter wonderland’. Leading onto Lake Baikal(Pearl of Siberia), which seems to attract the most attention in the Siberian region. Leading onto regions with marked resemblance to the Mongolian region with grasslands into inner Mongolia in China. A meditative route in all, just letting the pace lead the daily routine. One can also get off stations of interest and explore areas along the route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Irkutsk which is the station where people get off to go to lake Baikal. Tectonic movement destine lake Baikal to eventually become earths fifth ocean. it is the largest fresh water lake in the world. the scenery changes to more hilly region. The train track winds very close to the shores of the seemingly endless lake Baikal and provides for some really stunning landscapes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0397.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0383.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0415.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0355.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0356.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0373.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From time to time, there are some interesting scenes which just zoom by and you are left to think, did that really happen? Like old military equipment making their way to wherever that might be, loads of tanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0462.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some days we get to learn new Russian words; like when trying some snacks without myasa (meat). The trolley lady stops by and has a chat seemingly very interested about our Kindle and asking if we could make a call with it and trying to sell us some stuff. And making a very not impressed expression after hearing the price for just reading books. Kapustha is a kind of bread with stuffed cooked cabbage. tasty but too greasy. Along with hands and legs language there is a need to use picture drawings to get our ideas across, of course if the drawing is not too good a cabbage might end up looking like a heart from a sacrificial animal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0918.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple breakfast can cost about 10Euros. The beer we had was absolutely no good. But still far better than food running out near Baikal - apparently a reality during early Trans-Siberian journey days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0211.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fun DIY tip: The water heater gets broken down, the technician comes by and gets started with a screwdriver only and then it gives way to a wrench and some banging much similar to fixing an old CRT tv with a nice firm hit to the sides. “repair” is still progressing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day of the border crossing between Zabaikalsk and Manzhouli (China). We end up spending close to 10 hours including change of wheels to adapt to the new gauge in China. The picture below shows the two set of rails to accommodate different gauge sizes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0579.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all need to get off our carriages and wait till the wheels are changed. I try to sneak up on the workshop and catch some pictures of carriages being lifted and the wheels being changed, but I’m quickly stopped by the personnel, anyway here is some exclusive insider scoop!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0575.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0577.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the checks we were visited by 4 different sets of officers. The first one was like a warm up, came by chatted with us and even apologized  for speaking broken English. The next one came on all fours, sniffed around, looked very officer like Mr.Labradofficer (yes that’s an obscure reference to a sniffing dog and no he did not find anything illegal), then came a stout well built man who pressed Mr.Labradofficer to sniff a bit more, then came the customs, a young officer and an older officer. The younger spoke clearly more English and the older one seemed to be the funny side kick, repeating the commands of the officer with some delay and a cheeky smile ..’passport please’, ‘bags please’, finally leaving with a ‘goodbye please’. Then came the immigration officer we all know, this time embodied as a tough Russian woman, checking the passport at every different angle, with UV light, plain light, bar code scanner, with no light, asking us to stand under a light and looking back and forth a good minute. But left with a friendly smile and a greeting. All the checks were done on train owing to the fact we were no more than 30-50 passengers on the whole train at Zabaikalsk and we were the only ones in the 9 compartment carriage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The experience at the border checks of China was even more funny .. tsk makes one loose all fear of the dreaded border crossing with bullets whizzing by. This time we were visited by 5 sets of officers. The officers were very curious and very friendly, even for ‘random people you just met’ standards. One set of officers just came by to ask Cathy how she spoke so many languages so well and to ask for tips to learn Russian. One more came by with a camera and asked if they could photograph me for a mock customs check for advertisement purposes. Our passports were taken for checking purposes and returned after a 90 minute period&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Station&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;km&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Moscow&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Vladmir Pass&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;210&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Nizhnii Novogrod&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;461&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Kirov Pass&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;917&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Glazov&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1125&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Balezino&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1154&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Perm 2&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1397&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Ekaterinburg&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1778&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Tyumen&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2104&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Ishim&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2393&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Omsk&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2676&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Barabinsk&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3000&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Novosibirisk&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3303&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Taiga&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3532&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Mariinsk&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3680&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Krasnoyarskii&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;4065&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Ilanskaya&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;4344&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Nizheundisk&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;4647&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Zima&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;4902&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Irkutsk&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5153&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Sludyanka&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5279&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Ulan Ude&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5609&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Petrovskii Zavod&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Hilok&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5902&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Chita&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6166&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Karymskaya&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6262&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Mogoitui&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Olovyannaya&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Yasnogorsk&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Borzya&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6509&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Zabaikalsk&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6626&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Manzhouli&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6638&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all Russia has been a very pleasant experience, especially meeting all the interesting people along the way, be it the mid aged man who claimed to have worked in the french film industry (of course did not speak English) and could also sing a line of an Indian movie from the 60s just being really happy to have met an Indian and saying thanks for no particular reason, the little girl who shared her candies with such happiness without even understanding what we were talking, a young Russian from the outskirts of Moscow who was fascinated by America , the host at the youth hostel who relished upma (Indian breakfast/snack) we cooked and even asked us to stay longer. Yea nice people across all generations, its great to be reinforced with a possible inherent goodness even in strangers in a land and culture so far away.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Mother Russia</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Russia" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Mother Russia" /><published>2017-02-02T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-02-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Russia</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Russia">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/screenshot-0.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Getting there: Cheap flights with airBaltic transiting in Riga,Latvia(Schengen zone)-actually cheaper than taking a train from Amsterdam to Moscow&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Getting around: Single ticket in Moscow metro costs ~55Rubles (~0.8Eur) and can be used to travel any number of times without exiting the metro station, Taxis can be available with Uber or Gett taxi app&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*WiFi: Available at SVO airport on arrival terminal, rest of the city public hotspots have poor connection or require Russian mobile number&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Money: Visa and Mastercard are widely accepted and can also be used at supermarkets&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Language: English not widely spoken, so be prepared with some standard Russian phrases. Even better write it down and point-shouldnt be so hard with all the translation apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*See: The stunning old metro stations on line4, Red Square and surrounding landmarks (Moscow is lit up during night)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Tips:Be aware of illegitimate/unregistered youth hostels/accomodation. Carefully hold the departure slip which will be stamped on arrival at Russia (needed while exiting the country). Get Moscow Metro map and familiarise with stations of interest and travel directions (Russians are friendly(shock!!) - just ask and avoid opening with ‘do you speak English?’). If travelling with train make sure the Cyrilic characters match the name pronunciation. If you are in need for some spare electronic parts at the last moment, check pleer.ru. Buying national train tickets is possible on the language friendly webiste of Russian rail rzd.ru. Openstreetmaps has free maps for almost all regions of the world which can be downloaded and used on Garmin devices; get one for the country you are visiting - very helpful! Consider using xend.pay for making bank transfers (to pay for bills/invoices), they provide amongst the best exchange rates in comparison to banks (transferwise is limited in number of countries one can pay into). Use the following link https://secure.xendpay.com/signup/ur/U206565 and get 10euro as joining bonus on successful transfer. Consider applying for credit cards which do not charge the ~2% charge for using in a foreign currency (highly recommend Deutsche Kredit Bank)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG2052.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/DSC_1653.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We fly into SVO and had earlier tried to find the best possible option for getting from the airport into the city. booking a taxi before hand online is relatively expensive costing anywhere between 20-40 eur, but with the added convenience of english speaking driver. The other possiblity is to take the aeroexpress metro into belorussky station and change over to the corresponding line to get to the end destiantion, but with 22kg backpack + hand baggage it was not the most comfortable (would cost abut 600 rub per person). Instead we chose one of the mega players in the collaborative market, Uber and ended up paying about 13 eur to our hostel. We already warmed up our “hand and legs” language in the absence of understanding each others language. The driver tried to make some conversation about India and pointing to the temperature display, maybe asking why the hell was i leaving a warm country and ending up in -15C, or maybe asking me to drink more vodka since its not as sunny anymore… open to interpretation!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moscow has the vibe of the perfect immersionist experience if you are looking to get out of your comfort zone. cant decipher many of the cryllic characters, cant speak the language, cant get around in the metro, the music sounds so different, cuisine completely unknown, coupled with the mystery of a “former” communist country its a perfect mix to slip into a new world… of course mcd follows you everywhere if you understand the language or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG2104.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got off at the address of the hostel but could not find the building there was an old man/usher who showed us the way to our hostel by pointing to go around the building and go up the stairs, what a go around that was … we thought we entered some kind of a drug den. we were later to find out that there are lot of illegal hostels in moscow and booking.com listing does not mean legitimacy. Finally we checked into a very minimalistic hostel. Go there for the friendly people and local experiences but not if you want a very comfortable place to stay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using an aircon in moscow at -15 temperatures? believe it or not, the hostel turn up the heat till its a sauna indoors. also something we end up seeing in manzhouli&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we went to collect the tickets of our train journey. the office building was just as non descript as the hostel, all so anonymous with no billboards, but we are greeted by Natalia, a very warm and friendly person behind the counter who gives us much insight into the Moscow way of life. We are breaking stereotypes by the person, Russians are quite friendly and willing to help and tolerate our poor language skills till we are able to communicate whatever little we can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have lunch at the italian restuarant, Russian cuisine is not really vegetarian friendly and end up paying about 30eur for a good 4 course meal. Credit cards are accepted everywhere, the paywave rfid payment can also be used in metro stations and grocery stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the night we step out to go visit the red square, we also observe something we already saw flying into the city of moscow, they love their lights! all building are lit up on the outside. looks like they are recreating daylight and just showing off the grandeur of some the humongous buildings. Red Square is no exception. the sheer scale of the whole thing exudes dominance but one is still able to find some beauty in the midst of all that awe. the beautiful domes of st basilica. Just a stone throw away is an underground luxuruous shopping mall lined with marble.. classical irony. At this point the camera battery emptied and realisatin dawned that we did not have the charger along with us. Although we could not find the charger we were looking for, pleer.ru is a very useful resource. They have a big warehouse very close to one of the metro stations and can help to find most of generic electronic spare parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/DSC_1659.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/DSC_1662.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;we go subway hopping on line 4 the second oldest metro line with absolutely gorgeous metro stations, each of them having their own unique characteristics right down to marble colour, archways, ligthing and themes ranging from education, art, history, war/propoganda but real pieces of art. with people just rushing through the stations, we were taking time to admire the beauty of the place, some random person just walks up to me and gives me a russian miniature flag .. am i being marked?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG2095.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG2093.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG2078.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG2076.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG2073.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG2071.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG2070.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG2069.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG2068.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG2059.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Navigating the meto stations of moscow is like a mind puzzle , if  Be is to Б and Ef is to Ф, does Кра́сная пло́щадь lead to the red square?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG2075.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;fun fact: Yakutia region in russia has the lowest recorded temperatures upto -70C and is purpotedly recommended for people who want to stay young - the natural antiwrinkle solution&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up next: Do we freeze on the the trans-siberian express?? Stay tuned&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>