<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.4.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-04-16T07:15:51+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Asia Much?!</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Thailand</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Thailand" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thailand" /><published>2017-03-21T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-03-21T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/thailand</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Thailand">&lt;p&gt;*Getting there: Low cost flights with Air Asia. Border crossing over land also possible via road or train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Getting around: Abundant options of mini-van and private buses as well as government buses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Money: Visa/MasterCard accepted in most establishments (subject to minimum spending limit/ extra charges). All ATM charge a transaction fee between 200-220THB as of March 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Language: English widely spoken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*See: National parks, local food markets and beaches (of course).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Tips: Arms charge a flat transaction fee, so estimate your expenses and withdraw the necessary cash for the vacation in one go. If exchanging currency, compare among different operators exchange rates vary. Transportation is not on time ,so factor it in, if your estimated time of arrival is late in the night (street dog menace!). National parks accommodation and camping options were impressive (we tried Sri Phang nga). If landing in Phuket, take the airport bus into Phuket town (old bus stand) costs far less than the taxi. Scooters are an inexpensive way of getting around, daily rent cost somewhere around 200THB (license is normally not asked for).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thai/DSC_4424.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We fly into Phuket airport, the visa on arrival process is straightforward and short. We take the airport bus to Phuket town (old bus stand). The staff is very helpful and make impromptu stops based on the address information you give them. We decide to avoid the big cities and head off to Khao lak. It is about 90 minutes bus ride from Phuket and costs about 200THB. There are buses leaving approximately every hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Khao lak is on the West coast of Thailand. It is mainly a tourism oriented town and has abundant choices for accommodation, food and recreation for all budget spectrum. We stayed at the Dkaya hostel run by two sisters and were really impressed with the cleanliness and hospitality. One can rent scooters for the day as low as 200THB and explore the surrounding areas such as waterfalls, beaches and local landmarks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thai/DSC_4451.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thai/DSC_4476.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh the food! Here are some snapshots, cant talk too much about it (busy munching) ..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thai/DSC_4489.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exploring the local market at Khao lak was a feast for the senses even in the pouring rain. Shopping for fresh vegetables and spices and being able to cook them is definitely a memorable experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thai/IMAG0928.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thai/IMAG0930.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thai/IMAG0931.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thai/IMAG0932.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Khao lak was hit by the tsunami in 2004 and there are still many remnants, like this police patrol boat which was swept inland for more than a km.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thai/DSC_4492.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also many stories of survival and hardships which one gets to hear from the locals and some tourists. Such life altering experiences present a different perspective on life for the survivors, it is one of the many gifts of travel to hear and share those perspectives from locals and fellow travelers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thailand in general is a very pleasant country to travel in. The tourism infrastructure is top! Most of the people can speak English and are willing to help in whatever way they can even if the language skills are limited, the food is great, the scenery is varied .. it has something for everybody&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be vigilant, surprises can spring around the corner!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thai/DSC_4499.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first national park on the list is Khao Sok national park. We take a mini-van to get there and the driver has a particular driving style which can be described as ‘CRAZYYY’. Yes you cannot book that/not book that in advance. So sit back and see what you will get next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thai/DSC_4506.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Khao Sok national park area is much less touristic than Khao lak but more touristic compared to national park standards elsewhere. There are plenty of accommodation and restaurant options. Plethora of guides offering half and full day treks, canoeing adventure, night trekking,jungle survival trekking. We were not able to visit the floating camps on the lakes in the national park. It is also an activity that has many favorable reviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is also possible to go trekking through the forest in the dry season without a guide. The path is very well maintained with clear markings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thai/DSC_4519.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thai/DSC_4526.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some detours lead to hidden streams and clearings which are ideal to take a break and a swim maybe?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thai/DSC_4567.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thai/DSC_4571.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thai/DSC_4572.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thai/DSC_4576.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thai/DSC_4637.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thai/DSC_4650.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amongst the many national parks in the area, Sri Phang Nga is one. This time we choose to stay inside national park premises in one of the bungalows. The facilities are basic but comfortable. The camping area is also a great alternative provided one brings a tent along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thai/DSC_4687.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thai/DSC_4688.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thai/DSC_4720.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thai/DSC_4722.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The national park has many waterfalls which are a short trek away. The waters are very clean and inviting, the national parks have been very well maintained by the authorities and the locals visiting them also do their part of keeping the place clean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thai/DSC_4698.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thai/DSC_4704.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thai/DSC_4708.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next destination is on the east coast of Thailand in a city called Prachuap Khiri Khan, much less touristic than even Khao lak. It has a really nice beach inside of an air force station. Definitely, one of the hidden places. There are plenty of beach restaurants. So pick a cozy spot, order some food and drinks. You can then just sit back and relax there for hours with gentle ocean breeze and soothing wave sounds. Happiness can be found that easy in the simplest things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/thai/IMAG2627.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kob khun ka and definitely see you next time Thailand!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">*Getting there: Low cost flights with Air Asia. Border crossing over land also possible via road or train.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tour de Vietnam and Cambodia - Ho Chi Minh city to Siem Reap</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/HCM-SiemReap" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tour de Vietnam and Cambodia - Ho Chi Minh city to Siem Reap" /><published>2017-03-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-03-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/HCM_SR</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/HCM-SiemReap">&lt;p&gt;*Getting there: Flights between Saigon and Siem Reap. Buses or private taxis. We just chose to cycle most part of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Getting around: Tuk-Tuks are the most prevalent form of transport in Cambodia&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Money: Visa/MasterCard accepted in most major establishments. Most Cambodian banks charge anywhere between 3-5USD per transaction at ATMs. Bank of China was an exception to this rule&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Language: English not widely spoken in the countryside. Though you will come across plenty of kids with the brightest smiles welcoming you with a ‘Hello’ and many waves as you pass by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*See: The many temples around the Angkor Wat complex. Don’t miss Beng Mealea (offers a quite spot away from the tourist crowd). Local handicrafts being made. Apsara dance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Tips: Avoid the mid-day sun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3176.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When this trip was first being planned, the idea was to do most if not all of it over land and ferries.But as the finer details of planning showed up it was clear that on most stretches it was much cheaper traveling by air than otherwise. However, this stretch provided us an opportunity to go with an organized tour from Saigon,Vietnam to Siem Reap, Cambodia. It was opportunity to get close to the country and people. The experiences have not disappointed us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We chose Cambodia cycling, though there is still some room for improvement on the tour planning and coordination part and we faced some obstacles in the planning phase itself, the organizer Mr.Dara was proactive and ensured we had a safe and enjoyable journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The start of the trip was in Saigon with Mr.Trong as our tour guide for the Vietnamese leg of the journey. He is a very passionate cyclist and also has a very good command on English. We start our journey with a day trip to the Cu chi tunnels where the Vietnamese Communists and Americans waged a brutal drawn out battle against each other. The tragedies experienced in this place are immense. The exhibits describe how the local population fought with the limited resources available to them against a much more powerful combat force. Some ingenious methods like tunnels for housing whole villages, booby traps, reusing undetonated munitions, creating ‘smokeless kitchen’ underground ..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_2730.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_2734.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_2741.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_2754.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3046.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we bike to Tra Vinh over a total distance of about 50km. Biking along this route of the Vietnamese countryside is extremely pleasant. There is ample shade from all the coconut groves around us and this with the canals keep the surroundings cool. The cycling path is generally over village pathways lined with concrete slabs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_2767.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_2769.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_2790.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_2795.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_2814.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_2824.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_2838.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3126.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3131.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an abundance of coconut in the Mekong delta. We get to know that the Mekong originates in Tibet flows through Myanmar,Thailand,Cambodia before reaching Vietnam. Mekong literally means mother river. These waters really nourish the coconut plantations and produce some of the healthiest coconuts I have seen. The vietnamese make the most of this gift. Every part of coconut tree is made use of from using the nut itself for its water, making sweets, oil to using leaves to build shelters, to using the husk to produce fibers and in turn mats, to using the shells to make cooking vessels and heat containers and even furniture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some glimpses of local life&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_2799.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_2806.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_2823.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_2937.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3013.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cycling in the hot sun with temperatures touching well into 35C. Its a feeling of gratitude for every tree that provides shade along the way. It can be extremely refreshing to have some fresh fruit. So we stop regularly to have some fruits, drink some sugar cane juice. After meals on most days we rest like the locals by just taking a nap in hammocks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_2862.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On most days we get to eat like the locals from a street side noodle shop. Our guide also takes us to his former college to meet up with students from the English club. All experiences that make you feel like you are moving amongst the people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Tra Vinh we proceed to Cantho the next day with a cycling distance of about 80km. Cantho is apparently the biggest city in the Mekong Delta. At least from initial impressions, it is less crowded and chaotic than Saigon. If I were to go to Vietnam again it would definitely be on my list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way we visit a temple. Many Buddhists monasteries here help people in whatever capacity they can, providing accommodation to students (our guide himself had stayed in a monastery during his college days), providing language classes and of course providing counsel for distressed persons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_2886.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_2892.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_2893.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rice is extensively cultivated in the Mekong Delta and apparently they continuously grow the crop due to abundance of water&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_2712.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_2715.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_2906.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_2992.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_2994.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The welcome one gets from the kids is just heartwarming, be it Vietnam or Cambodia you can see them just getting so excited to a see a bicycle with tourists passing by and they come running into the courtyard with a bright smile and the most enthusiastic wave and big ‘Hello!’, few greetings get more genuine than this!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_2919.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_2952.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3399.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some days we also need to cross over channels with a ferry (extremely basic sometimes)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3101.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3106.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3108.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3115.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3118.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3208.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We visit the floating markets of Cairang, the next day and finish off with 75km of cycling. Nowadays mainly reduced to merchants buying items wholesale and of course as tourist showpiece. The goods being sold are advertised on a long pole at the front of the boat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3222.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3236.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3238.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3246.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3262.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3264.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3273.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3275.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we transfer to the border of Cambodia, where Trong hands us over to the Cambodian team and we meet Mr.Lucky who will be our tour guide till Siem Reap. Not before having to pay bribes on both sides of the borders and clearing the immigration process. If somebody in Vietnam and Cambodia who can change this is reading, bribes not nice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Transferring into Cambodia we notice the temperatures are already much hotter, not as much shade and the trails are dustier. Still excited to be in Cambodia, here is a picture of two happy cows!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3414.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucky is a very people person and takes us to meet villagers along the way. We just make an impromptu stop at a local house and we warmly welcomed by a teacher who teaches English at the local school and is hosting the prayer and meals for the villagers. He is a very cheerful and warm person, and conveys the grim history of the country, followed by its dire poverty and current situation of lack of educated young people all with a smile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3476.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We next stop by a local handloom place and are greeted by the woman who runs the place. Her house and workplace are in the same shelter. A very empowered person!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3477.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3480.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3481.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are visiting Cambodia in March and the temperatures and mid-day sun is something one is better off avoiding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we transfer to Siem Reap and I’m so looking forward to visiting and taking in the temples around the Angkor Wat complex. But before that here are some quirkiness on the road that make you wonder what is going on!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3489.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3495.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3497.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3863.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We check into Golden Butterfly in Siem Reap, its a very comfortable, luxurious place with helpful,competent staff. Definite worth a recommendation. A much needed place of rest from all the days of cycling and heat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3498.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And good food keeps following us! One thing that was definitely new to me was the use of Lotus in dishes.. yummy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3516.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evening we bike around the countryside of SiemReap in relatively cool temperatures. Meeting local farmers with our guide Lucky, we get to taste palm wine, taste palm fruit, eat some palm sugar. Palm trees seem to be the symbol of Cambodia and the Cambodians make the most out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3529.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3530.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3546.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3862.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are now primed and ready to take in all the temples of Angkor Wat complex. But first, a 3 day pass of 62USD must be purchased. Transactions in USD are ubiquitous in Cambodia, and in the touristic city of Siem Reap all transactions are done in USD including for the laundry. Siem Reap is definitely not cheap and is in stark contrast to the rest of Cambodia, even locals agree that Siem Reap is ‘easy money’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We first visit the temples of Banteay Srei. It is constructed largely from red sandstone. The temple is in contrast to Angkor Wat temple in the sense that it is not a towering structure. But the grandeur shows up in the very intricate carvings throughout the complex. It was originally dedicated to the Hindu God Shiva&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3644.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3690.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3691.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3729.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3758.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3762.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3773.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3776.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3777.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3780.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3783.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then head cycle to visit the Kbal Spean (River of thousand Lingas). The riverbed is carved with many lingasand the then Kings of Angkor thought that lingas carved into the riverbed sanctified and blessed the waters which eventually flows into Siem Reap. The area and the area has many beautiful carvings which depict the multitude of Hindu gods Brahma, Vishnu and Shiva. Like most archaeological sites in Angkor complex they have also fallen prey to extensive smuggling. To get to the site, one has to walk through well paved forest of about 2km.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3813.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3815.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3838.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3861.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we set out on the so called Grand circuit covering the temples of Pre Rup, East Mebon and Ta Som, Neak Pean and Preah Khan. All the temples have their own unique characteristics. The scale of the constructions and dedications never fail to impress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3869.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pre rup was originally constructed as a temple for Shiva and is thought to be a site of cremation for the royal family. It is characterized by a high central platform housing five towers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3872.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3873.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3875.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4283.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ta Som complex is a Buddhist temple with occasional change to Hinduism and back, which seems to be a recurrent theme in the history of the region. The temple has a lot of trees that have grown into the complex, giving the very first feelers of the famed jungle temples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3899.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3901.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3904.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3908.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3915.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3923.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3925.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3926.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neak Pean is a temple built on an island and the temple itself is partially submerged. The central platform is on a sculpture of two intertwined serpents. It is a Buddhist temple with a statue of Avalokiteshwara in the form of a horse who rescues sailors caught in bad sea. The temple has four worship corners for the four elements of earth, water, fire and air. Traditionally it was used to perform healing rituals for the wounded and the sick. Each of the corner was thought to have balanced the imbalances in the sick and wounded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3937.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3941.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3942.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3948.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3951.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3956.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preah Khan meaning ‘Royal Sword’ was built as a war memorial to honor the father of King Jayavarman 7 for defeating the Chams. The entrance to the temple has a grand sculpture of devas and asuras churning the ocean of milk with Vasuki the serpent. Such Hindu symbols are very prevalent in most of the temples. It was also thought of as a political tools used widely by the then kings to balance their perception among Hindus as well as Buddhists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3958.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3959.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are big intricately carved statues of Garuda on the outer walls of the temple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3962.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3963.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3970.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3975.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3991.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3994.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the temple complex is unrestored and natures seems to have made its home amongst the Gods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_3998.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4000.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4001.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4004.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day is planned for the so called small circuit covering temples like Angkor Wat, Angkor thom, Bayon. We decide it might be a good idea to catch the sunrise over the Angkor Wat. How was it? Not a must do in my opinion. You are likely to be hoarded amongst the tourist crowd like here&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4011.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4012.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To catch glimpses like these&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4015.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4016.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4023.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, you cant escape the grandeur of this mega complex of a temple. Which in spite of its grand scale does not overwhelm, there is a certain characteristic that exudes harmony. It was originally built as a temple to Vishnu and has gradually transformed into a Buddhist site of worship over the many decades of change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4084.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4077.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4029.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4030.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4031.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4032.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4035.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4037.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4054.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4055.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4057.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4088.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4080.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The temple complex is separated into different layers. It was also used a method of allowing or denying entry for different classes of the society. There are many intricate carvings on the level accessible to common people as well. These carvings depict the power of the army of the then Khmer kings, their victories in war, mythological stories as well as depiction of hell and heaven and the associated actions which take people there. Platform of mass education?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4058.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4067.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4072.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We later proceed to cycle along the moat of Angkor Thom, the last enduring city of the Angkor times. Taking a deviation from the very busy road of the south gate we ride along the moat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4117.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4119.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4122.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We end the cycling trail at the east gate which is almost deserted and just as well preserved as the south gate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4135.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We continue onwards to Bayon, the temple which stands at the center of Angkor Thom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4163.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4164.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first glances the many mysteriously smiling faces are not clearly visible&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4168.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4170.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you approach the temple, you are surrounded by them looking over you from about 37 towers. It is not clear as to whose face is depicted on this tower, but the serene mystical characteristics are not asking the question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4226.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4229.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4231.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4242.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4243.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We cycle down to the Ta Phrom temple. It is one more temple where nature and human architecture have agreed on harmony and peace with each other. The trees at the site are as much a symbol of the temple today as is the architecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4251.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4254.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4258.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4260.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4262.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4265.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4272.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4274.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the final day we explore Beng Mealea and we are blessed with some cloud cover for the 60km ride from Siem Reap. Just when you think you have seen it all, Ben Mealea surprises you. It was originally built as a temple dedicated to Vishnu. The site is largely unrestored and one can really appreciate the hard work that goes into restoration. For the layman it is basically staring at a mound of stone blocks trying to re-imagine the glory seen through the eyes of the designer. The surrounding vegetation has generously grown into the complex and become part of it. Coincidentally, the center of the complex supposed to house the worship deity has completely collapsed and now has a giant tree growing right in the middle of it. Maybe a sign of what new age divinity should be for the times we are approaching?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4321.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4322.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4323.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4325.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4328.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4333.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4335.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4340.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4341.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4342.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4346.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4347.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4348.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4364.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4372.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4375.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/hcmsr/DSC_4405.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Orkun tomtom and Lea sun howey Cambodia!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">*Getting there: Flights between Saigon and Siem Reap. Buses or private taxis. We just chose to cycle most part of it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ho Chi Minh City</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/HCM" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ho Chi Minh City" /><published>2017-03-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-03-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Saigon</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/HCM">&lt;p&gt;*Getting there: We flew in from Osaka through Hong Kong. For the more adventurous, taking the train from Hanoi or even riding a motorbike or bicycle from Hanoi are possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Getting around: Public bus network exists. Uber and Grab seem to be the most used services with their corresponding apps, they even offer motorbike taxis which are generally half the price of a taxi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Money: Visa/MasterCard accepted in most major establishments. Most Vietnamese banks charge a fee for drawing cash from ATMs. Techcom bank was an exception to this rule&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Language: English widely spoken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*See: Stroll around district 1, visit the colonial buildings which include the post office, party building. The local market with multitude of fresh produce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Tips: Avoid ATM withdraw fee by using Techcom bank ATMs. Use Uber/Grab for getting around. If you want to be a pedestrian avoid the streets during rush hour (a motorcycle will also follow you on a footpath).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vietnamese visa on arrival procedure is straightforward. After paying the fee and presenting the invitation letter, filled application form and a passport photo; the visa is stamped and handed over. Getting from the airport we took the taxi at the arrivals hall, on second thought maybe hailing an Uber taxi might have been cheaper. The streets of Saigon are filled by motorcycles and the overwhelming impression is that you are besieged by them at all times and they can appear out of any direction… magic!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2534.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2538.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our homestay called the Vietnamese Homestay is a very cozy place. It was a former cafe being run in the home where the owner actually grew up. It is decorated effortlessly and gives an impression of an oasis of calm even when the motorcycles are zooming by on in the street in front.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2542.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2543.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2547.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2612.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also met a hypno cat with shining eyes, and one can get near it only when the eyes are closed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2561.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2563.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The culinary experience is something else. The tropics come alive on your taste buds here. There is an abundance of vegetarian food&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2555.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2560.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2673.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2675.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2678.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit to the local market is a colorful and hungry experience. There are so many fresh produce and new fruits and food to try out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2571.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2573.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2574.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2575.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2576.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2577.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2579.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2580.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2581.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2582.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2583.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2584.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Street Coffee’ is apparently a thing to do in Saigon on the weekends. People just drop by and have coffee by the roadside cafes during weekends.  The coffee is really strong served with condensed milk and has a method very unique to Vietnam for preparation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2626.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2618.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;District1 has most of the notable sightseeing spots in Saigon. So a short stroll after the coffee should check those boxes as well&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2631.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2634.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2641.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2642.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2645.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2657.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2658.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2660.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2692.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vietnam/DSC_2693.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gaum un and Xin chao Saigon!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">*Getting there: We flew in from Osaka through Hong Kong. For the more adventurous, taking the train from Hanoi or even riding a motorbike or bicycle from Hanoi are possibilities.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Kyoto</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Kyoto" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kyoto" /><published>2017-02-20T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-02-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Kyoto</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Kyoto">&lt;p&gt;*Getting there: Peach airlines has many low cost routes ending in Osaka. From Osaka it is a short ride on the JR express line to Kyoto&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Getting around: Metro and bus network is very extensive. Taxi is possible as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Money: Visa/MasterCard accepted in most establishments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Language: English not widely spoken, so be prepared with some standard Japanese phrases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*See: The many temples around Kyoto, visit the flea market, Japanese simplicity and attention to detail&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Tips: Get the ICOCA Haruka card (available only at Osaka airport). This provides the tickets to and from Kyoto at a discount price. As well as a card that can be used on the bus and metro. ATMs at 7Eleven all dispense cash also for international cards. Duty free shops in Kyoto and Osaka are clearly marked (for purchases above 5000Yen - purchases cannot be opened before leaving Japan).Daiso is the equivalent of a one dollar shop and can be quite handy to find items for short use. Tourist bus in Kyoto ferry passengers to the main highlights. It is possible to parcel items internationally from the Osaka airport either by air or ship cargo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As our plane approaches for landing at Osaka we are hit by strong winds. The plane engine can be heard revving up trying to keep the plane steady in the turbulent winds. In spite of all the power, along the descent there are times where the plane moves involuntarily to the side in the face of all the high winds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We land safely at the airport. Osaka airport is very tourist friendly with comprehensive tourist information and well marked layout. Also what was impressive was the autonomous toilets, I’m sure I don’t have to describe them in detail. But impressive piece of design nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our accommodation is relatively small but extremely well designed. There is the now obligatory automatic toilet (washlet as they call it), electronic controls for everything from the washlet, to the exhaust, lights, even one to convert the bathroom into a clothes dryer. Compact, minimal and functional!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2366.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2367.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2368.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stay very close to the Kiyomizu Dera temple. The construction of the temple stage was done without using any nails and only by interlocking wood joints. Quite an impressive feat when one looks at the scale of construction. We decide to go watch the sunrise over the temple one early morning. If you plan to do it, skip it. Its not really all that impressive. But we still got some nice shots and were able to walk the shrine complex in peace and silence that is most often not possible in most of the touristic temples in Kyoto. This also gave us the chance to chat to some locals who come regularly to walk around the complex and  exercise together. Most temples in Kyoto require an entrance fee to be paid. Unfortunately there is no group ticket for the shrines in Kyoto. Most of these shrines are also crowded with tourists and if you are looking to find a quite place to sit and meditate look beyond Kyoto.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The temples in Kyoto we visited all are very ‘progressive’, they have taken into consideration the needs of generations as they move along. We see small shrines around main complex which are dedicated to gods of good luck, better results in examination, finding the perfect life partner and so on. The two stones below for example is a test to find if your partnership will last. Procedure : Close eyes and try to walk from one stone to the next, if you reach the next stone then success!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_1949.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_1932.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_1934.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_1936.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_1939.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_1958.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many more temples to visit around Kyoto, the Ryozen Kannon temple was the only temple we visited where there was not as much of a tourist crowd. All temples require there own separate entrance fee. Ryozen Kannon also has memorial for soldiers who have died in the various wars. There are also earths from war cemeteries from around the world housed in the shrine, very opportune moment to reflect on the real price of war and violence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2078.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2083.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yasaka shrine is also a beautiful temple complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2127.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2132.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2140.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2143.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is hard to miss all the young women dressed up in Kimono around the temples. It seems to be like a thing to do in Japan. One can rent the Kimono complete with the shoe, handbag, parasol and all the accessories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kinkaku-ji temple (golden temple) is another favored tourist spot. It is quite ironical, that the object of marvel is the Golden temple and it seems to be decoupled from the spirit of what the philosophy is trying to say. It captivates the mind nonetheless!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2341.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2345.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2350.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2352.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2355.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quality of food in Japan is impressive. The portions are minimal, but the presentation and quality make up for it. We tried out a tofu restaurant serving Yudofu which is tofu skin which solidifies on top of simmering soya milk. It is very tasty! The meals come in sets and are quite pricey. There are plenty of vegetarian options and items typically include tempura (deep fried vegetables), yudofu (tofu skin), rice, pickled vegetables, tea, wasabi and ginger, soy sauce. The meal set cost about 2500Yen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_1972.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_1970.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_1973.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wandering around the streets of Kyoto, you will also get to see a lot plastic meal sets on display to show what you can expect once you order a meal set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2026.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2027.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2028.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also big on the culinary experience is Matcha! Don’t miss it. The Japanese have gotten inventive with it, you get everything from Matcha ice cream, Matcha candy, Matcha waffles, Matcha jelly, basically anything you could think of .. if there is something you think of and cant find it in Japan, maybe you should quit your job and sell it in Japan! The frothy green tea served in about 100ml quantities is really one more reflection of Japanese attention to detail and simplicity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2177.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2014.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2015.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2017.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exploring the smaller streets can also open a new world of culinary adventure, areas in Gion seem to have a high concentration of such restaurants&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2063.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also the food from the convenience stores are very wholesome and good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_1929.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The simplicity and attention to detail in everyday life in Japan is so inspiring. Even the simplest of construction,landscaping and calligraphy exude simplicity and beauty&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_1980.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_1977.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_1982.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_1985.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_1989.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_1994.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2150.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2152.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2165.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is this Rakusho cafe near Yasaka shrine selling excellent Matcha sweets and also comes bundled with an extremely beautiful garden! yes i did use extremely!! The Matcha sweets definitely match up to the beauty of the garden. The sweets are prepared fresh and must be consumed before 2 days after preparation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2093.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2096.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2098.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2105.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2107.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The general culture is of appropriate respect to one another. This is also seen on the road,in ques, at restaurants and public places in general. Physical barricades to enforce rules seem to be kept to a minimum but just simple marking on the floor seem to suffice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2035.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A must do is also to stroll the crowded (often by tourists) streets of the local market (Nishiki Market) called the ‘Kitchen of Kyoto’. There are multitude of fruits, vegetables, meat, fish, tea, pickled vegetables, spices, snacks, souvenirs. One of the most popular snacks seems to be sticky rice dipped in sweet soya sauce, quite tasty! Top it up with grapefruit juice, using the fruit skin as a container itself, served by a very friendly chef.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2036.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2038.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2040.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2044.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2048.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The flea market at the Kitano Tenmangu temple is open once a month (25th if i remember right). It is a nice place to look through all the articles on sale giving a glimpse into Japanese culture. Yes it is very crowded and the area it covers is vast. Things like antique tea sets, paintings, toys, music records, clothing, chopsticks, arts and crafts, even plants are all on display.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2336.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2282.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2297.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plum trees start to blossom in Feb and is a very beautiful sight drawing also a lot of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2301.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2305.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2312.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2313.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2324.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2326.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2328.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are likely to come across many wayside shrines in small housings or relatively grand complexes or peaceful corners dedicated to different Gods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_1920.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2059.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2060.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To experience some aspects of local art and culture, plan a visit to the Gion Corner. Tickets can be bought at the tourist office or directly at the venue. Unfortunately for the winter session the flower arrangement and Bunraku puppet show were canceled. However we were still able to get a glimpse of tea ceremony complete with music of Koto(six stringed instrument) and flute, Gagaku court music (performed traditional in the royal court), Kyogen theater (comical theater) and  Maiko’s dance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2184.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2197.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2206.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2208.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2209.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2213.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2214.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2222.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2243.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2248.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have time or you need to wait for your next flight. Check out the ‘Sky View’ area in the Osaka airport. There are free shuttles to and from the terminal. It is a nice little tucked away quite place from the busy terminals. Osaka airport is built on reclaimed land and there is a nice presentation detailing the technical aspects of the construction. There are also explanations of the ecological measures taken to minimize the impact of the airport on the environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2407.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2421.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2428.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2434.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2446.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2453.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2459.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2472.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2483.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2505.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2515.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/japan/DSC_2529.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arigato Gozaimas and Sayonara Japan!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">*Getting there: Peach airlines has many low cost routes ending in Osaka. From Osaka it is a short ride on the JR express line to Kyoto</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Shanghai</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Shanghai" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Shanghai" /><published>2017-02-19T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-02-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Shanghai</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Shanghai">&lt;p&gt;*Getting there: High speed train, as well as normal trains from other major cities&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Getting around: Taxi. Metro system is very extensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Money: Visa/MasterCard accepted in very few establishments. Mobile payment is the preferred mode of payment. Cash otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Language: English not widely spoken, so be prepared with some standard Chinese phrases. Even better write it down and point-shouldn’t be so hard with all the translation apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*See: Having been there for an evening only, we can only recommend the night skyline when all the buildings including the Pearl tower lights up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Tips: If you are taking the metro to reach Pudong airport make sure you take the metro earlier than 9:00pm. No metro to the international airport of Pudong after around 10:00.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Japan was a flight away from Shanghai. So we headed down to Shanghai for the flight and spent an evening in the city. Here are some pictures from the financial heart of China where apparently billions of dollars gets traded everyday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/DSC_1854.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/DSC_1873.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/DSC_1880.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/DSC_1884.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/DSC_1892.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/DSC_1900.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also headed into the old market of Shanghai, trading in all sorts of quirky ‘goods’ which includes live animals and fighting crickets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/DSC_1859.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/DSC_1860.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most part of the traveling experience in China seems to be setup to create a mini chaos. It is really hard to understand how an international airport in the financial heart of a country, can have a metro which does not service it all through the night! You heard it right. If you plan to take the metro to Pudong airport make sure you leave well in advance and in any case not later that 9:00 pm. Even on the same line, there is a transfer station on the way to the airport and if you do not get  to this transfer station before 10:00pm you will not reach the airport since the metro stops 2-3 stations before that; throwing you into the hands of taxi drivers waiting to make a quick buck. If somebody in Shanghai who can change this situation is reading this blog, please do!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">*Getting there: High speed train, as well as normal trains from other major cities</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hangzhou - ‘City of Heaven’</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Hangzhou" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hangzhou - 'City of Heaven'" /><published>2017-02-13T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-02-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Hangzhou</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Hangzhou">&lt;p&gt;*Getting there: High speed train, as well as normal trains from other major cities&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Getting around: Taxi is the easiest option from the train station. Metro does not serve all localities. Bus network also exist but multiple changes might be required depending on origin and destination. bicycle sharing system with many docking stations around tourist destinations as well as city center exist (location of these stations are not well documented).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*WiFi: Actually we did not attempt to connect to local city hot-spots&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Money: Visa/MasterCard accepted in very few establishments. Mobile payment is the preferred mode of payment. Cash otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Language: English not widely spoken, so be prepared with some standard Chinese phrases. Even better write it down and point-shouldn’t be so hard with all the translation apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*See: Take a stroll along the vast west lake and its many causeways (aim for weekdays for relatively less tourist crowd). Visit the many towers and temples around the lake. Experience sunset on the east side of west lake Let the tranquility, simplicity and harmony of the peony garden seep in. enjoy the musical fountain show every evening at 6pm. Visit the tea museum. Visit the mountain area around Lingyin temple and take in the idols of Buddhism towering on in the rock faces above. Stroll amongst the ever peaceful premises of the temple and spare some time for contemplation. Visit the old city part of Hangzhou and savor the street food (find the green bean pancake if you can).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Tips: Get the tourist card from the tourist information which serves as a contact-less payment card for the buses and a free pass for the bicycle sharing system (free for the first one hour). The card cost about 600yuans with a deposit fee of 300yuans. Try fresh local breakfast (normally runs out around 09:30) - soy milk, steamed buns, noodles, or a choice of many other dishes. Also try local family made steamed dumplings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marco Polo on his travels in the 13th century, described the city as the most beautiful and magnificent on his travels. After the ordeal in Beijing, the feeling was very similar for us. Arriving night in Hangzhou, nothing is needed more than a warm shower, a nice meal and a good sleep. As simple as that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/IMAG0853.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The west lake area is very beautiful and has inspired many kings,poets and artists alike. The Su causeway was built by the famous poet Su and is one amongst a series of 6 causeways along the lake. This draws a large number of tourist to the area. It is not really possible to avoid the tourist crowds, the best bet for a peaceful stroll along the causeway is during the weekdays.  Some areas like the peony gardens are relatively less crowded. It also offers a chance to experience Chinese landscaping bringing into harmony the various elements in a garden. West lake covers a very large area of about 7sqkm. so some parts are more crowded than others. To watch the sunset over the lake we headed to the east side of the lake. The infrastructure around the lake is very well developed maybe in part due to Hangzhou being the host for the G20 in 2016. There are ample opportunities to sit down and take in the scenery, have a snack, drink a cup of coffee or tea, watch the locals performing the ‘square dance’. After the sunset we walk around the lake and find an area of unusually high concentration of people (even for China). It was the daily gathering to watch the musical fountain show of 15 mins.  It is a nice sight, if you do not mind being cramped in a large crowd it is worth the experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0841.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0845.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0846.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0847.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0852.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0854.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0881.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0883.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0886.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0891.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0899.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0909.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0911.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/DSC_1827.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/DSC_1833.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lingyin temple was built by an Indian monk during the Jin and  Song dynasty. Entrance fee must be paid to get into the mountain reserve and to the temple as well. It is possible to cycle all the way upto the entrance of the Lingyin temple reserve using the bike sharing system. Upon entering the reserve, a pathway to the left leads to the statues carved out of limestone rock faces paying tributes to Buddha, Bodhisattva, mythological characters and the eminent personalities in the Song dynasty court. Walking amongst them gives you the feeling like they are towering and watching over you. Maybe the sense that pilgrims actually wanted walking into a place of pilgrimage. The entire site is covered with many trees along with pristine flowing stream and many ponds adds to the tranquility of the reserve. The site is now a UNESCO world heritage site, but some of the statues seem to have been deliberately defaced. The information boards do not provide any information for the same. Nonetheless, it is a very unfortunate that such acts of vandalism occurred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/DSC_1697.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/DSC_1698.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/DSC_1699.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/DSC_1707.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/DSC_1715.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/DSC_1718.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/DSC_1719.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/DSC_1725.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/DSC_1731.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/DSC_1732.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/DSC_1733.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/DSC_1734.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/DSC_1739.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/DSC_1740.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/DSC_1753.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/DSC_1762.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tea museum in Hangzhou is accessible by the tourist bus. There is even a city sharing bike station to drop off the bikes. The entry to the tea museum is free. The museum documents the history of tea originating in China and spreading to the rest of the world. Elaborating on the evolution of the tea culture, different tea types and tea ceremonies. There is also a multimedia presentation on traditional tea preparation detailing everything from preparing the tea kettle, tea glasses, amount of tea, water temperature and soaking time. The tea culture is so refined that every type of tea has its own optimal tea set made from varying materials. Enough to say you will never look at tea the same way again. Once you are there, make sure to try out the green tea hotel close by, amazing food!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/DSC_1778.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/DSC_1783.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/DSC_1788.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/DSC_1802.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/DSC_1806.JPG&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, the street food in old Hangzhou is a must! There are plenty of vegetarian options. The basic idea of the whole food adventure is to navigate through the crowd and not get bogged down by the chaos, treat the whole market as your dining place and pick and choose an unforgettable multi-course meal. Our most memorable food was a green bean crepe with a crunchy core. We had never had this ever in the parts of China we had traveled through. It even came with its own story from the chef, apparently the crunchy core represents bad spirits and people take a particular pleasure in deep frying them. Of course there are many other delicious items like Vegetable deep fried rolls, Sweet sour noodle, Fresh tofu marinated in soya sauce, Grilled aubergine filled with glass noodle and vegetable, the list goes on and the food street is open!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0864.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0861.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0858.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0860.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0877.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">*Getting there: High speed train, as well as normal trains from other major cities</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nightmare in Beijing aka how not to arrive in Beijing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/BeijingNotMuch" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nightmare in Beijing aka how not to arrive in Beijing" /><published>2017-02-12T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-02-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Beijing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/BeijingNotMuch">&lt;p&gt;*Getting there: Flights. Beijing is connected to rest of China with an extensive fast speed train connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Getting around: Metro though sometimes not very intuitively marked is easy enough to use. We did not use taxis&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Money: Visa/MasterCard accepted in very few establishments. Mobile payment is the preferred mode of payment. Cash otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Language: English not widely spoken, so be prepared with some standard Chinese phrases. Even better write it down and point-shouldn’t be so hard with all the translation apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Tips: Always book your accommodation beforehand. China has some very weird rules for hotels accepting foreigners (else end up spending the night in a McD)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arrive at Changping bei late in the night. Unfortunately no experience really worthy of mention, since we were worn down by spending the night in a McD outlet. How did we end up with this not very exclusive offer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently, all foreigners must be registered at the local police at every point of stay in China which mean a lot bureaucratic steps for the hotel staff, this coupled with possible punitive measures in case of mistakes running into thousands of RMB, the hotel staff will just flatly refuse to register foreigners. So watch out! book before hand if possible and check if foreigners will be accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We end up spending the night in McD, this experience is enough to make one feel cranky,tired and in general not very good. Its a moment to spare a thought to people who have had to/have to go through such schedule on a regular basis like emergency shift workers, people working multiple jobs out of compulsion, soldiers, policemen. Yea so no pretty pictures today!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have an early breakfast in a noodle chain called Mr.Lee , they offer vegetarian dishes as well. Later we head down to Beijing Nan which is a 2 hour metro ride. We hope to check into a hotel in the station to get some sleep. Surely, a high speed train terminal in the capital of China will have a hotel in the train station that accepts foreigners right? Yes i asked the question to contradict the obvious answer and say No!! The logic definitely beats me. So we just head to a cafe and spend the 5 hours before we can board the train to Hangzhou&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Beijing Nan station has loads of cafes and restaurants and shops in the station. The station is not laid out in a very intuitive manner and can take some time to figure out where to go. For example, you can board the high speed train through a common line for all high speed trains which goes through a common waiting area (really long queues) or a dedicated counter for only the particular high speed train one needs to board (numbered 1-11 if i remember right).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The high speed train platforms are accessible only to passengers of the train about to depart otherwise it is out of bounds. In general a very orderly system. There is room for luggage at the front and back of each compartment. Food can be bought in the pantry. Non reserved tickets can also be purchased with the risk of not finding a place to sit.The trains travel at a max speed of about 303kmph and just whizzing past the landscape on elevated tracks gives a feeling of as though looking down on miniature models of towns as they actually pass by on the ground. It is indeed awe inspiring how China is surging ahead with infrastructure development and they have very ambitious plans to also bring the high speed rail to span even the north of the country which would reduce our 32 hour journey from Manzhouli to Beijing to about 5 hours. One can see clear contrasts between big industries and high rise buildings gaining on small villages and cottages. Guess its not a very unfamiliar story for most of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0813.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0820.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0821.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0840.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up next: Kinsay or the ‘City of heaven’. Amongst Marco Polo’s travel it was apparently the most beautiful city on his travels.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">*Getting there: Flights. Beijing is connected to rest of China with an extensive fast speed train connection.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Aboard the train from Manzhouli to Beijing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/china/2017/02/11/Man_Bei.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Aboard the train from Manzhouli to Beijing" /><published>2017-02-11T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-02-11T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/china/2017/02/11/Man_Bei</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/china/2017/02/11/Man_Bei.html">&lt;p&gt;*Booking: Can be done on the official China Rail website but apparently need a Chinese mobile number and ID to do it, on ctrip website but it is delivered to only major cities as of Feb2017, there are many agents who book the train tickets for a charge of about 6USD per ticket (change of train is considered a new ticket)+delivery charge+payment surcharge if using PayPal or credit card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*WiFi: available but only for Chinese mobiles and in any case the landing page is almost always in Chinese&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Money: No card payment possible on train&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Language: English not widely spoken, so be prepared with some standard Chinese phrases. Even better write it down and point-shouldn’t be so hard with all the translation apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Tips: Smoking is permitted on trains in designated areas. Food can be bought on the train either in the canteen or the pushcarts. 220V charging points in every compartment of the soft sleeper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We head down to the train station to board our train to Beijing. Train station security checks are straight forward. id check, ticket check followed by xray of baggage and body scan. people are not allowed on the platform until the train arrives. everyone has to wait in waiting rooms and they are opened once the trains are ready to board. tickets are checked before boarding. we had booked soft sleeper which is a 4 person compartment with baggage place under seats and also some “attic” space. Hot water is available, food and drink carts pass by often. 220V charging points are available so is WiFi, access with some China specific apps. The facilities in general are OK. However the toilets are not that clean and sometimes the water in the wash area or sink can run out (as it happened).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0630.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t plan your trip in the high season or around it and try to avoid peripheral stations like changping bei (bei is north in Chinese. Beijing was the capital of the north in old China) since getting to Beijing Nan(Nan being south in Chinese) (for the high speed train) would be a hassle (2 hour metro ride, or about for a dist of about 112 km)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have the company of a very friendly family with roots in Mongolia. we hear stories of traditional celebrations with family accompanied with food, drink, music (impromptu singing). Roasted nuts are a staple snack to chat over. We are told stories of favorite past times in  their culture, punctuated in between by a very spunky 3 year old kids talk. we are also offered tips of navigating Beijing and offered some desert oranges&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scenery passing us by is very varied. From the grasslands of inner Mongolia to hilly regions proceeding down south. Vast farmlands to crowded cities. All the variety of scenery and people breaks up the monotony of the train travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0642.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0644.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0654.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0666.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0696.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0700.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0707.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0748.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0760.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0765.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG2256.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG2274.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG2275.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traveling is always fun hearing some stories from the local part of the world&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently foreigners or foreign looking persons are not very common on these trains. Result, i get one more celebrity or peculiar zoo animal experience (just kidding!). When we walk into the pantry, the chef welcomes us like we are the captain of the train and especially puts on the apron and makes it a point to personally come collect our order. He does not speak much English but is generally very interested to talk to us and wants to take the best possible care of us guests. For lunch we have some chopped potatoes with vegetables and rice, at the end of the meal he comes by again and offers to pour some hot water into our rice bowl, apparently a way of finishing the meal. The celebrations of the Chinese new year still seemed to be going on even though the date was Feb10. He also offers to make sticky rice sweets just for us. Very friendly! The captain of the train and some train staff are also in the pantry and crew in general are very jovial and joke around (like commenting that a comb will be gifted to a bald crew member present in the group for the spring festival). A meal costs an average of 40Yuan. There are also push carts that pass by in the compartments selling Chinese version of porridge, sweets, chips, soft drinks, steamed corn and lunch set meals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smoking is allowed on Chinese trains between compartments and if the doors don’t/wont be shut the smoke enters the cabins and stays there. So be prepared for that, we had a hellish ride in the second half of the train ride because of that. Cigarettes are even sold on the push carts!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the time around the Chinese new year and was such a joy to look at the houses irrespective of how rich or poor it looked, to be decorated with red lanterns and Chinese writing of prosperity and good wishes. this was a constant theme in all the villages and city we passed through on the way to Beijing. Even the life-stock (cows, donkeys, sheep) were sometimes marked with red. We even caught glimpses of a dragon dance very briefly. Later as the sunset and we were passing through various villages and cities there was this non stop fireworks lighting up the night in some spectacular show. A very interesting and unexpected experience!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0724.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0743.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0768.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0800.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been a  pleasant journey with friendly co passengers, a very warm train crew, stunning landscape from Inner Mongolia to Beijing, watching the festivities of spring season in the villages we rush by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up .. Nightmare in Beijing??&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">*Booking: Can be done on the official China Rail website but apparently need a Chinese mobile number and ID to do it, on ctrip website but it is delivered to only major cities as of Feb2017, there are many agents who book the train tickets for a charge of about 6USD per ticket (change of train is considered a new ticket)+delivery charge+payment surcharge if using PayPal or credit card.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">In inner Mongolia,Manzhouli</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Manzhouli" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="In inner Mongolia,Manzhouli" /><published>2017-02-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-02-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Manzhouli</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Manzhouli">&lt;p&gt;*Getting there: Manzhouli has its own airport. But train is cheaper, direct trains from Beijing are available. Speed trains do not serve Manzhouli as a destination as of 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*WiFi: Poor. Public wifi hot-spots cant be connected to without a Chinese mobile number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Money: Visa/MasterCard accepted in very few establishments. Mobile payment is the preferred mode of payment. Cash otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Language: English not widely spoken, so be prepared with some standard Chinese phrases. Even better write it down and point-shouldn’t be so hard with all the translation apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Tips: Dress warm in Winter!!!! Explore the local food culture and maybe go shopping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Manzhouli is a very peculiar city, brightly lit, big buildings and shopping malls. This is in sharp contrast to the border town in Russia. Approaching Manzhouli already felt like Vegas, a sparkling city blanketed otherwise by nothingness and shadows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0585.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Manzhouli is really cold in winter, but apparently still warmer and expecting upto -40C normally.We check into a hostel with attached bathroom for 10Eur a night. The hostel has a very distinct Mongolian feel along with idols in Genghis khan, Mao, Stalin and Lenin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0606.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0607.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0608.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We meet a very skilled player of a type of Chinese stringed instrument called Guzheng and he courteously plays for us a piece epitomizing the mountains and rivers. Such a beautiful piece it was, it was so easy to envision along with him the sound of water in the music itself. he has been playing the instrument for 13 years and on a work-away vacation and plans to become a professional musician later. This is a description of the instrument from chinawhisper.com website “The Guzheng is a Chinese plucked zither. It is made of 18-23 or more strings and movable bridges. People believe that it has been invented during the Warring States Period (475-221 BC).  The performer pluck the strings at the right portion with right hand, and left hand presses the string on the left side of the bridge to produce pitch ornamentation and vibrato. The skilled player can create sounds that can evoke the sense of waterfall, thunder, and even the scenic countryside.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;object&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;autostart&quot; value=&quot;false&quot; /&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;src&quot; value=&quot;/assets/china/music.mp3&quot; /&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;autoplay&quot; value=&quot;false&quot; /&gt;
&lt;param name=&quot;controller&quot; value=&quot;True&quot; /&gt;
&lt;embed src=&quot;/assets/china/music.mp3&quot; controller=&quot;true&quot; autoplay=&quot;false&quot; autostart=&quot;false&quot; type=&quot;audio/mp3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/object&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Loved the Manzhouli food culture. The biggest shopping mall in town has a full floor dedicated to a eatery with a wide variety of cuisine in different stalls on offer. I choose a kind of Korean dish with rice and cooked vegetables in a hot stone bowl. The idea is that the ingredients get slightly scalded by coming in contact to the hot stone bowl. The ingredients have to mixed together and must be stirred continuously. Sea weed soup to go along with it. The portions are really generous. There are other options as well like vegetables deep fried in oil and topped with seasonings, hotpot on a conveyor belt, steamed buns. The fate of the vegetarians are looking up! Average meal costs about 10-18Yuan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0593.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0597.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0598.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0610.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/china/IMAG0612.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;China has their own network of credit card providers, so visa is not entirely accepted at all merchants. but finding a bank with ATM is not very hard. What is also very common is mobile payment. We would also see it elsewhere in China, they are used by all service providers from street food vendors to shopping malls and beyond. It seems to be a social media network, chat platform and payment platform rolled into one. Extremely convenient, maybe not very privacy friendly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Manzhouli seems to offer much more in the Summer and is also the peak season. We leave for Beijing after an overnight stop.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">*Getting there: Manzhouli has its own airport. But train is cheaper, direct trains from Beijing are available. Speed trains do not serve Manzhouli as a destination as of 2017.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Transmanchurian-the train journey through the snow globe and beyond</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Transmanchurian" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Transmanchurian-the train journey through the snow globe and beyond" /><published>2017-02-04T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-02-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/transsib</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Transmanchurian">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0145.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Booking the ticket: rzd.ru can be used to book national routes online on an English page. International routes have to bought through an agent or in person at the train station. So get creative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Amenities on the train: Hot water for drinking. Can also be used to prepare ready made meals. Canteen is available on train but with very limited vegetarian options (Cup noodles can also be bought). Drinks can also be bought. Food can also be bought at the platform where the train stops (Stop time range from a couple of mins to an hour or more). Shower has been apparently discontinued. Toilets are kept very clean. Ample storage space for luggage (we had two 90L backpack which could easily fit in the space above our compartment). Doors in the first class compartment can be locked from the inside. Blankets and pillows and towels are provided. Compartments are vacuumed once a day. Charging points (220V AC) are available (4 points for every compartment).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*WiFi: No Wifi is available on the train&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Money: We paid with cash. But the canteen seemed to have a card reader (maybe only works if the station halts at a major station)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Language: English not widely spoken, so be prepared with some standard Russian phrases. Even better write it down and point-shouldn’t be so hard with all the translation apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Tips:Temperatures in the cabins are maintained at a comfortable 22-24C. Warm clothes needed only for the outside. Toilets are locked for 15 mins before arriving and after departing from every station. Most of the shopping for groceries and food can be done beforehand at the many convenience stores in and around the train station. ATM machines available at the Yaraslavsky train station. At Zabaikalsk (Russian border town to China) the wheels of the compartments are changed and passport checks are done in the train (depending on number of passengers), the toilets are closed during this time so make sure to listen to natures calls and use the toilet at Zabaikalsk station before boarding the train again. Available options to book first class compartment(SV) - 2 berth compartments, second class(Kupe) - 4 berth compartments, third class (platskart). Options seems to be available for gender specific compartments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Trans-Siberian rail has three main rail routes (journey can also compose of shorter legs) Trans-Siberian which runs from Moscow to Vladivostok (9298km over 6days); Trans-Mongolian goes through Russia,Mongolia and China, starting at Moscow-Ulaanbaatar-Beijing (7826km about 6days); Trans-Manchurian which goes through Russia and China, Moscow-Beijing(8988km over 6days). We booked our ticket online at rzd.ru. Online ticket is provided which must be exchanged for tickets at the train station (counter or automated machines).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG2221.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Historically, the Trans-Siberian rail was envisioned by the Tsars to transform Russia in the industrial age  in the 19th century among other goals. The construction of the epic rail-route of the 19th century was shadowed by financial issues, geographical and meteorological challenges and  human resource problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We take train 20 on the trans-Manchurian rail between Moscow and Beijing and plan to get off at the Chinese border town of Manzhouli. Yaraslavsky station is the departing station. After passing through the security check we end up in the waiting room for the train to arrive. The station is surprisingly empty of crowd for a major station in the capital of the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our train arrives 30 minutes before departure and we make our way to board the train. Looking forward to getting comfortable in our first class cabin. Our passports get checked and the obligatory attempt by the train attendant to pronounce my last name, don’t know how many different variations I have heard of it, but will add Russian to it now. At the end of succeeding to say my name, the Provodnitsa purses her lips gives a thumbs as if to congratulate herself on managing such a superhuman feat of pronunciation. The cabins are really very comfortable (first class eh, not often you can afford that!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Provodnitsa who are in charge of keeping the compartment in order have a very interesting personality. They are generally women and always keep an eye out what people are doing in the corridors of the compartment and outside the train usually with a frowning look. No need to reach for your armour yet, they are generally friendly and very competent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0564.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two person cabins in the first class, with a water heater at the end of each compartment, dispensing boiling water all the time. toilets are very clean and there are just 3 cabins occupied out of 10 cabins, so very sparse.Which is quite natural since we are traveling in the low season. We are given blankets and bed spreads. The canteen is also well equipped basically you can buy everything on board or at the station stops provided one is willing to pay a little bit more. There is enough storage space to store at least two 70l backpacks at the top and about two 50l backpacks under the seat. Inside temperature are a comfortable 20-24C, main cabins are isolated through two doorways. Yes, the outside is very cold.The outermost doorways already had ice creeping up on the frames and handles, so don’t lick the door handle!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0226.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did i already say it is really comfortable in first class? just sit back, read a book, play some games, snack or drink and watch the country pass by and comment on the peculiarities of a country running past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0217.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0219.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0249.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0250.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0272.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0304.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0311.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0316.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0317.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0319.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0488.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0510.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0557.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0560.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The train stops along the way and there are opportunities to get off and walk about and buy some things, the time in all train stations are in Moscow time but there are about 11 time zones in Russia which lead to some very peculiarities. One of the shortest days we encountered was on the third day. getting up at around 8 am and getting into darkness already at 2pm (Moscow time). The worst is at Zabaikalsk which is a full 6 hours ahead of Moscow but the trains still follow Moscow time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The approximate average speed is 60kmph and this lets you watch the towns big and small pass you by, sunrise and sunsets many. From the populated regions European Russia with  Yekaterinburg and passing through Vladimir which has amongst the oldest churches in Russia. Leading onto Taiga and Siberia with steady landscapes that can be subtitled ‘winter wonderland’. Leading onto Lake Baikal(Pearl of Siberia), which seems to attract the most attention in the Siberian region. Leading onto regions with marked resemblance to the Mongolian region with grasslands into inner Mongolia in China. A meditative route in all, just letting the pace lead the daily routine. One can also get off stations of interest and explore areas along the route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Irkutsk which is the station where people get off to go to lake Baikal. Tectonic movement destine lake Baikal to eventually become earths fifth ocean. it is the largest fresh water lake in the world. the scenery changes to more hilly region. The train track winds very close to the shores of the seemingly endless lake Baikal and provides for some really stunning landscapes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0397.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0383.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0415.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0355.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0356.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0373.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From time to time, there are some interesting scenes which just zoom by and you are left to think, did that really happen? Like old military equipment making their way to wherever that might be, loads of tanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0462.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some days we get to learn new Russian words; like when trying some snacks without myasa (meat). The trolley lady stops by and has a chat seemingly very interested about our Kindle and asking if we could make a call with it and trying to sell us some stuff. And making a very not impressed expression after hearing the price for just reading books. Kapustha is a kind of bread with stuffed cooked cabbage. tasty but too greasy. Along with hands and legs language there is a need to use picture drawings to get our ideas across, of course if the drawing is not too good a cabbage might end up looking like a heart from a sacrificial animal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0918.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple breakfast can cost about 10Euros. The beer we had was absolutely no good. But still far better than food running out near Baikal - apparently a reality during early Trans-Siberian journey days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0211.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fun DIY tip: The water heater gets broken down, the technician comes by and gets started with a screwdriver only and then it gives way to a wrench and some banging much similar to fixing an old CRT tv with a nice firm hit to the sides. “repair” is still progressing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day of the border crossing between Zabaikalsk and Manzhouli (China). We end up spending close to 10 hours including change of wheels to adapt to the new gauge in China. The picture below shows the two set of rails to accommodate different gauge sizes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0579.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all need to get off our carriages and wait till the wheels are changed. I try to sneak up on the workshop and catch some pictures of carriages being lifted and the wheels being changed, but I’m quickly stopped by the personnel, anyway here is some exclusive insider scoop!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0575.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/russia/IMAG0577.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the checks we were visited by 4 different sets of officers. The first one was like a warm up, came by chatted with us and even apologized  for speaking broken English. The next one came on all fours, sniffed around, looked very officer like Mr.Labradofficer (yes that’s an obscure reference to a sniffing dog and no he did not find anything illegal), then came a stout well built man who pressed Mr.Labradofficer to sniff a bit more, then came the customs, a young officer and an older officer. The younger spoke clearly more English and the older one seemed to be the funny side kick, repeating the commands of the officer with some delay and a cheeky smile ..’passport please’, ‘bags please’, finally leaving with a ‘goodbye please’. Then came the immigration officer we all know, this time embodied as a tough Russian woman, checking the passport at every different angle, with UV light, plain light, bar code scanner, with no light, asking us to stand under a light and looking back and forth a good minute. But left with a friendly smile and a greeting. All the checks were done on train owing to the fact we were no more than 30-50 passengers on the whole train at Zabaikalsk and we were the only ones in the 9 compartment carriage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The experience at the border checks of China was even more funny .. tsk makes one loose all fear of the dreaded border crossing with bullets whizzing by. This time we were visited by 5 sets of officers. The officers were very curious and very friendly, even for ‘random people you just met’ standards. One set of officers just came by to ask Cathy how she spoke so many languages so well and to ask for tips to learn Russian. One more came by with a camera and asked if they could photograph me for a mock customs check for advertisement purposes. Our passports were taken for checking purposes and returned after a 90 minute period&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Station&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;km&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Moscow&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Vladmir Pass&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;210&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Nizhnii Novogrod&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;461&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Kirov Pass&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;917&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Glazov&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1125&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Balezino&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1154&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Perm 2&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1397&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Ekaterinburg&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1778&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Tyumen&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2104&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Ishim&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2393&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Omsk&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2676&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Barabinsk&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3000&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Novosibirisk&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3303&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Taiga&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3532&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Mariinsk&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3680&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Krasnoyarskii&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;4065&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Ilanskaya&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;4344&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Nizheundisk&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;4647&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Zima&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;4902&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Irkutsk&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5153&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Sludyanka&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5279&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Ulan Ude&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5609&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Petrovskii Zavod&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Hilok&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5902&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Chita&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6166&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Karymskaya&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6262&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Mogoitui&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Olovyannaya&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Yasnogorsk&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Borzya&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6509&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Zabaikalsk&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6626&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Manzhouli&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6638&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all Russia has been a very pleasant experience, especially meeting all the interesting people along the way, be it the mid aged man who claimed to have worked in the french film industry (of course did not speak English) and could also sing a line of an Indian movie from the 60s just being really happy to have met an Indian and saying thanks for no particular reason, the little girl who shared her candies with such happiness without even understanding what we were talking, a young Russian from the outskirts of Moscow who was fascinated by America , the host at the youth hostel who relished upma (Indian breakfast/snack) we cooked and even asked us to stay longer. Yea nice people across all generations, its great to be reinforced with a possible inherent goodness even in strangers in a land and culture so far away.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>